. So, let us come to the another video what is bit serving dot exe and what is the purpose
of the bit serving dot exe and how threat actor will abuse this bit serving dot exe for a
malicious purpose ok. So, what I am what are the things I am discussing in this video you
can see that in the active incidents if the threat actor belongs with the bit serving
service ok. So, it will very helpful when you are investigating that type of case.
So, let us talk about what it is bit serving ok. So, bit serving is nothing but background
intelligent transfer service this is one of the service which was introduced by Microsoft
in Windows XP operating system and it was used to download or uploading a large files
of large files or a large data from the internet ok. Basically in overall view so this
was used by the Windows update to update your operating system ok. So, this is the overall
view of bit serving let us take it simple I am not going depth in theory ok it was kind
of boring. So, my motive is to explain all the things in a practical way ok.
So, we need to understand overall brief of bit serving why bit serving was used by the malicious
threat actor by the threat actor to to a malicious things ok. So, let us take your Windows
update your Windows update will update at the particular time. So, that all the things
are responsible for the bit serving ok background real intelligent transfer service it will
take the responsibility for your Windows update as well as your you want if you want to
update any other drivers or a third or a third party application can also use the bit
serving to download or upload a data or they can use for an update ok.
So, let us take an let us come with the let us come with the how threat actor will abuse
these bit serving to for a malicious purpose ok. So, in order of understanding so, the
bit serving used to to download or upload data right. So, the the same way the threat
actor can a can able to use this service to download or upload a large files of data
to the internet or from the internet right ok. So, these are the commands I will explain
this commands in a practical ok. Let us come with the mitre tactics it came with you it
has a differentiation tactics ok. So, way it came in a different situation let us think
about that ok. For example, your target organization added firewall tools there is some
restriction like the threat party application can not able to upload a data upload or download
a data from the from or to the internet. So, that time your malicious executable can
table to do that right your your malicious executable can table to download or upload anything
from the internet or from the server right. So, that time you can use this bits admin
to bypass that restriction ok. So, because bits admin is clearly a Windows internal
tool right. So, it is a it is a Windows internal tool. So, absolutely your firewall or
your antivirus or your EDS solution will allow that allow that thing allow the bits admin
job to do the do the responsible thing right right. So, for that it came with the
claims under the different aviation tactics also it came in a position. So, let us think
about your Windows update. So, when you are giving your Windows update later so, it will
ask for a time right. So, if you are giving a 2 o'clock it will wait till 2 o'clock and
it will start an update at 2 o'clock ok. So, this will create. So, the bits admin will
create a scheduled time for a Windows update with a with a job name called update or any
random names ok. And it will start a update at short player 2 o'clock ok. So, this is the
background intelligent transfer service will take a responsibility for all the all the
things ok the persistence and the creating a scheduled time and a scheduled job and everything
ok. So, let us comes with come with the practical ok. So, I will let us open a Windows
official. I will use the bits it is let us create a job we need to create some job ok create
I will create a job name of course, let us see it for some time ok. We have created a job
with this name and let us search it. Let us add a file sorry I just use an acceptable
bits admin slash add file and you need to give the name for the job basically we are
downloading one of the malicious file from the Internet this is the file mimic ads. So,
add a file parameter with the course name course that was the job name and I am going
to save this in users slash user, and I will name it as a bits job.exe ok.
So, let us go to the directory and we will see what happening inside the picture directory
when I am executing this command. So, let me it for some time it will create a bits job ok
yep. So, now you can see there is some TMP temporary file was added into the picture
directory with the BIT EFT dot TMP ok the temporary file was added. Now, we have created
and added the file added the job file successfully. So, let discuss about some routine
things ok. So, how we can investigate this how we can investigate if the threat actor created
any bits or bits that means job ok. Let us use this command bits admin list list verbose.
So, verbose will give additional information like creation time and modification time
what was the job and what was the job and all ok. So, here you can see the GUID and display
this was the job, job name the course and we have created. And now we are the download
download state status was suspended and one of us this was the owner and the bits admin
was created at this time and the modification time ok. And the job file ok see this was
the job ok. Absolutely this was a malicious file mimicad.exe. So, now if you are a threat
analyst you can understand ok this was the malicious file malicious executable malicious
URL that was added by the threat actor into the bits admin job ok. So, you can clearly
go and delete that job ok. So, by that you can stop the threat actor from that point ok.
So, this is how you can able to investigate the bits admin ok listed on job yeah it listed
on one job there is only one job a scheduled. So, let us come up with your routine
and bits admin slash let us download this mimicad.exe into our machine. I already told
bits admin is used to upload our download data. So, now we are thinking as a threat
actor we are downloading a malicious file from the internet using the bits admin ok bits
admin ok just we resume the job resume COU or AC ok. Now, the job was resume you can
see the command job resume let us download this bits admin slash download course on second
ok ok ok sorry the parameter will be complete ok ok I just you know it is admin slash
complete the job name was course ok see the job completed and our mimicad.exe file
was created under the directory pictures because we gave the picture directory to download
the bits admin. So, you here you can see the directory which we have here ok with the
name bits a bits job ok. So, this is how the threat actor will abuse the bits admin
to to deploy their ransomware or else to download download the second stage of payload
from the internet or they can they can use for they can use for a ransomware deployment
or else ok. So, let us take an example of a ransomware
deployment in this bits admin. So, the threat actor will host the ransomware
executable in one of the network service like file server or SMB server they will
transfer that ransomware executable across the state using the bits admin ok. So, the main
focus of the bits admin was it will it will evade the defense ok it will easily evade
the defense your EDR solution or your firewall or your antivirus software will own care
about what happening in the bits admin ok. That is why the threat actor using the bits
admin to to the to do your malicious malicious stuff inside the machine ok.
So, hope you enjoyed this video I have I have shown everything in a practical way and how
how you need to investigate and all ok hope you enjoyed the video we will see in the
next video. Thank you.